BILAL **HANEEF**

0315 8144251

Portfolio

in LinkedIn

G Github

Karachi, Pakistan

Bilalhanif848@gmail.com

Medium

Kaggle

SUMMARY

In my academic journey as a software engineering student at Karachi University (UBIT), I've dedicated myself to the world of data science. Over the past two years, I have gained practical experience in various areas such as Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, and NLP. I have also published articles on machine learning models and aim to utilize my expertise to drive innovation, skills, and ability to work effectively in a team-based environment.

EXPERIENCE

PaySys Labs Pvt. Ltd. (Karachi)

Associate Data Scientist (Full-Time) · July. 2024 -Present

Phoenix Technologies (Karachi)

ML Engineer (Full-Time) · Feb. 2024 - Apr. 2024

• Proficiently managed projects using computer vision methodologies like object detection, tracking, and segmentation through YOLO & SAHI models.

Folio3 Pvt. Ltd (Karachi)

Artificial Intelligence Intern · Jul. 2023 - Sept. 2023

• Contributed to Folio3's machine learning projects, worked on vector databases, and embeddings, and created feedback loop pipelines for the model.

Proxima AI (ICCBS-KU)

Data Science Intern · Oct. 2022 - Mar. 2023

• Made easy-to-use dashboards for better data access, gathered data from different places using web scraping, worked on machine learning models, and created practical DL models.

EDUCATION

Karachi University - UBIT

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering (BSSE) 2020 - 2023

Government Degree Boys College

Intermediate 2018 - 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera)

Deep Learning Specialization (Coursera)

NLP with Classification and Vector Spaces (Coursera)

Statistics For Business Analysis (365DataScience)

Optical Character Recognition MasterClass (Udemy)

Data Analysis With Python (FreeCodeCamp)

LangChain For LLM Application Development (DeepLearning.ai)

SKILLS

Domains

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Computer Vision

NI D

LLMs

Aws Cloud

Azure Cloud

Vector Databases

Languages

Python

С

Bash

Html / Css

Sql

Libraries

TensorFlow

Pytorch

OpenCV

Keras

Scikit Image

NLTK

LangChain

Scikit Learn

Selenium

Flask

FastAPI

Librosa

PROJECTS

Image Style Transfer Paper Pytorch Implementation

o It takes a simple & style. image and applies style to the simple image.

GenView (AI-Based Interview)

 LLM-driven interview system that collects interviewee data, poses questions, and assesses responses for accuracy.

Bone Fracture Identifier

It predicts bone fracture from an image with accuracy.

Next Word Prediction Using LSTM

o It predicts the next word based on its training corpus.

Query X

o It extracts information from any PDF upon request.

Real-Time License Plate Extractor

It captures license plate information in real-time.

Student Exam Performance

It uses student information to forecast scores in another subject.